Viewers all over the world, thank you. Thank you for your time.
I hope you are enjoying your time.
Time with Jesus - wonderful!
Hallelujah!
As I look at true believers, many Christians, I do not forget the many insults,
I do not forget the many persecutions,
I do not forget the many temptations they endure to maintain their Christian life.
Are you with me?
Injustice, pain, the opposition they endure to maintain their walk with the Lord.
Anything close to Jesus receives attack.
I think I'm going to build my message this morning around this.
Hallelujah!
I'm going to call it, 'The Secret Of True Believers'
because it is my secret - people don't know.
They see it as pain; they see it as a punishment.
Like what Job's wife said to him, "You say, you are a friend of God, God loves you so much.
Why are you going through all this pain, all this agony?"
Job said to his wife, "Why are you saying this?
Someone gave you butter, salad and later now gave you bitter leaf.
Why can't you take it?"
We have been eating the salad for so long.
and when bitter leaf now comes, we should take it.
Life is both sides - positive and negative.
Hallelujah.
Let's take our reading from the book of James 1:1-4.
That is our reading.
But in other books you will find this that will help you:
2 Corinthians 11. You take your reading from verse 23 to 29.
Are you there?
And also the book of Matthew 10. Take your reading from 19 to 20.
That will also help in your reading.
1 Thessalonians 5. Take your reading from verse 1 to 10.
That will also help.
'The Secret Of True Believers' - your secret.
Of which you don't know that it is your secret. It is your weapon.
Why is it your weapon? - We talk about it today.
Hallelujah.
James 1:1: "James, a servant of God and of the Lord Jesus Christ,
to the twelve tribes scattered among the nations: Greetings."
Trial and temptation - this is all we are hearing today.
Trial and temptation.
James 1:2: "Consider it pure joy..."
But today, we consider it as sorrow, crisis, pain.
But the Bible here says, "Consider it pure joy..."
Can you consider trial as pure joy?
Insult - pure joy?
Persecution - pure joy?
Opposition - pure joy?
This is what the Bible is saying here.
James 1:2: "...my brothers and sisters, whenever you face trials of many kinds"
Poverty, hardship, sickness, disease, stagnation could be your trial.
Okay?
James 1:3: "because you know that the testing of your faith produces perseverance."
James 1:4: "Let perseverance finish its work so that you may be mature and complete, not lacking anything."
Take your time and read from that verse 4 down.
I have given you those books that will give this message today.
Lord Jesus, we thank You.
Let Your Word in our hearts.
You should be ready right now, the prayer point given to you the last two to three sundays.
Lord, release my spirit to follow You; I have surrendered.
Say to yourself, "Release my spirit, Lord, to follow You; I have surrendered".
Your heart is very important.
Your heart must be at its best for God.
Your heart cannot be at its best without being spiritual.
Your heart must be at its best because the Spirit expresses itself through the heart.
Tell your neighbour.
The Spirit of God expresses itself through my heart.
I can't hear you.
[The Spirit of God expresses itself through my heart.]
Yes, the Spirit of God expresses itself through your heart.
That is why you must have freedom of your heart, a free heart - liberation.
You need it because the Spirit expresses itself through your heart.
Can you see the connection of your heart?
Your heart is His prayer room, strong room.
Why is it secret? - It is your secret.
Couldn't you hear? - Let your trial be a joy.
Hallelujah.
In life, we do have days, weeks, months and years that come with enormous challenges -
poverty, hatred, persecution, insults and so on and so forth.
What do we do as Christians when they come?
Believers may have challenges but our challenges are not like others.
As a believer, you may have challenges.
You know what I mean by 'challenges' - they could be sickness, poverty, could be this or that.
Our challenges are not like others.
They are to strengthen our desire and determination for God,
to improve us, not impair us.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
What do we do as Christians when they come?
The Bible says, "Watch and pray".
In one of the verses I gave you.
"Watch and pray."
How can you watch and pray?
It means you must discipline your heart before prayer.
You cannot watch for God without a disciplined heart.
'Watch and pray' means you must discipline your heart before prayer.
How do we discipline our heart?
Something that does not qualify for meditation does not qualify for conversation.
I'm telling you the process.
What are you meditating?
What does not qualify for your heart does not qualify for your mouth.
Are you with me?
Tell your neighbour.
What does not qualify for meditation does not qualify for conversation -
means, speak what you believe, say what you believe.
If I say, "Stand up for prayer!", if you don't believe, don't stand up.
If I say, "Sit down!", if you don't believe, stand!
But today, when I say, "Stand up!" - "Hm, man of God said, 'Stand up!'." You will stand up.
When I say, "Let us pray!" - you don't believe, yet you pray.
"In the name of Jesus!" - you don't believe and say, "Amen!"
"In Jesus' name!" - you don't believe what I'm saying and you say, "Amen!"
The whole thing has now become a national anthem.
Faith is not a hobby. We take our faith as a hobby.
There is no alternative for our faith.
How can we discipline our heart?
We submit to panic and you say you are a Christian.
When I say, "Hey, there is a lion somewhere there!", you say, "Where?"
That is the question you ask me - "Where?"
And I say, "There!"
Mere hearing the roaring - "Where is my bag?"
From that moment, you will not close your eyes for prayer again.
If I say, "Let us pray!", you say, "No, I cannot!"
Because a lion is around, you have to...
"In Jesus' name. Amen."
If the lion comes close, you say, "T.B. Joshua, the prayer has not sent the lion away.
It is still very close".
If the lion now kicks the door, you will abandon me here.
We should be still and not submit to panic.
Okay.
"Let us pray."
"Rise up and let us pray."
Can you see?
My brother is looking at the other brother, "When will you stand up?"
We believe in majority instead of God's authority.
"Let us stand up for prayer."
Okay, good!
Sit down.
By what authority are you doing this?
Authority that I put on suit!
Authority that I'm standing in front of you!
"Let us respect this man and stand up."
That is it.
If not, you don't believe what to say.
We should be still and not submit to panic.
That is our problem.
When you have a little pain in your heart - "Ey."
"What happened?"
"Ah, the thing has started."
"What started?"
And begin to do the right thing.
It is when you are still and not panicked that you can begin to do the right thing.
You don't do the right thing in a panic moment.
We should take control of our situation instead of being afraid.
Take control instead of being what? - Afraid.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Sometimes discouraged but not defeated
Cast down but not destroyed
There are times I don‘t understand
But I believe it‘s turning around for me
I’ve had struggles and disappointments
There are times I felt so alone
Some of my friends they let me down
But I still believe it’s turning around for me
Around for me around for me
Around for me it’t turning around for me
I can see the breaking of day
God is making a way
A change is coming for me
If I stand strong and believe
There's no reason to doubt
I know He's working it out
It's turning around for me
And it won't always be like this
The Lord will perfect that concerning me
And sooner or later it will turn in my favour
It's turning around for me
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Did you listen to that?
That song hit you.
It hit you.
You must take control of your situation instead of being afraid
because satan himself, the cause of crises and challenges, has been defeated.
Yes, that is what you should know.
The cause of those challenges you are facing -
poverty, sickness, disease, affliction, stagnation, temptation, persecution, opposition -
the cause, satan, has been defeated.
When adversity comes, as a true believer, welcome it.
True believers greet adversity as a friend, greet challenges as friends.
Whatever it is, greet as a friend.
That you are a believer, you may have affliction, challenges
but your challenges are not like others.
We must learn that there is value in the challenges.
The situation that looks impossible - there is value.
There can be no promotion without examination.
There is value in the situation that looks impossible.
That is why people like me can be here today.
True believers must have determination not to listen to the panic of the moment
but to find the quiet voice of counsel.
Pause and listen to what the Holy Spirit has to say concerning the matter.
That sickness may be to stop you awhile in order to prepare you for a new level in life.
That stagnation may be to reprepare you, to redirect you, to improve you.
It's a transit point to connect you.
Transit point - when you are going country to country,
there is a place where you have to stop to connect your flight.
That is the challenges to connect you to the future you desire.
Transit what? - Transit point.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When we listen to the Holy Spirit, He will protect us from the pitfalls of every enemy.
Continuously praying in the spirit and listening to His voice
will protect you from your daily challenges.
I know a place I can always run to
In times of distress, confusion and fear
But when my enemy surrounds me
Father I know I'm free
For You keep me and guide me
In the shadow of Your wings
In the shadow of Your wings I know I am safe
In the shadow of Your wings I find relief
For You will hold me and You'll guide me
With Your righteous hand
I find rest, peace of mind
In the shadow of Your wings
In the shadow of Your wings I know I am safe
In the shadow of Your wings I find relief
For You will hold me and You'll guide me
With Your righteous hand
I find rest, peace of mind
In the shadow of Your wings
I am safe in the shadow of Your wings
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You may be seated. Thank you.
Did you listen to that?
In our daily challenges, you need to find enough calm to think clearly and react diligently
and not submit to panic.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The challenges we are facing is just this: Our heart is not in one accord with our mouth.
When our heart is not in one accord with our mouth, whom are we talking to?
It is when our heart is in one accord with our mouth, then, we can bring Jesus on the scene.
Then, we can bring the Holy Spirit, Spirit of the Father into our hearts.
When we say, "Jesus!", our heart is not in one accord with our mouth.
"Amen!" - our heart is not in one accord with our mouth.
"Hallelujah!" - our heart is not in one accord with our mouth.
So, can you see? All what we are doing?
Ask your neighbour, "Did you pray for the situation you are in today?
Did you?
Did you confess the situation you are in today?"
It is what we have been saying, what you have been saying in the name of Jesus
is not such in heart.
What you have been saying in the name of Jesus, in the blood of Jesus,
"Amen", every day, is not such in heart.
So, this is what I mean.
Our heart is not in one accord with our mouth when it comes to God's Word.
Speak in the name of Jesus! Shout in the name of Jesus!
Our heart is not in one accord with our mouth.
Did you pray for this situation you are facing today?
This means, what you have been saying - "In the name of Jesus!" - is not such in heart.
No! It is not such in heart!
"In the name of Jesus! Father, bless me!
Father, give me this! Father, give me that!"
What you are saying is different from what is in your heart.
We begin to bring Jesus on the scene
or bring the Holy Ghost, the Spirit of Father into our heart,
when what we are saying is in one accord with our heart.
Like I have said:
As I look at true believers, I do not forget the many insults, persecutions, hatred,
temptation, opposition they endure to maintain their Christian life.
I salute them.
We are soldiers in the army
We have to fight or we have to die
We have to hold up our Saviour's banner
We've got to hold it up until we die
We are soldiers in the army
We have to fight or we have to die
We have to hold up our Saviour's banner
We've got to hold it up until we die
We are soldiers in the army
We have to fight or we have to die
We have to hold up our Saviour's banner
We've got to hold it up until we die
The SCOAN Sunday Service
All the soldiers in the house, let me see your hands up!
One more time!
We are soldiers in the army
We have to fight or we have to die
We have to hold up our Saviour's banner
We've got to hold it up until we die
Let me hear you say:
We are soldiers in the army
We have to fight or we have to die
We have to hold up our Saviour's banner
We've got to hold it up until we die
The Church is marching on
The gates of hell shall not prevail
We are soldiers in the army
We have to fight or we have to die
We have to hold up our Saviour's banner
We've got to hold it up until we die
You may be seated. Did you listen to that?
As I look at true believers, I do not forget the many insults, persecutions, hatred,
temptation, opposition they endure to maintain their Christian life,
to walk with the Lord.
Anything close to Jesus receives attack.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
These challenges force us to look deeper.
Tell your neighbour, "These challenges force us to look deeper".
Tell your neighbour what he does not want to hear and see what will happen.
Okay. Say to your neighbour, "Your mouth is smelly".
These challenges force us to look deeper, explore possibilities,
increase our desire and determination for God,
pray and dream of other ways that might have been ignored.
Can you see the value in crises, challenges?
Just say to your neighbour, "Hey! Please, you are smelly!" and see what your neighbour will say.
By what he is saying, it will tell you, you will know that he is not a Christian.
But now he is a Christian.
Tell your neighbour, "Now, you are a Christian.
Let challenges come and see whether you are a Christian".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
These challenges force us to look deeper.
Tomorrow, just look for your best friend.
Give him a test.
Just come and say, "Ha, I never knew you were a thief".
"I'm a thief? I'm taking you to the court!"
"My brother, come! It is not like that!"
Challenges force us to look deeper.
"I never knew you were not my friend."
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Without being tested, as a Christian, our genuineness cannot be determined.
Tell your neighbour, "Your genuineness cannot be determined without being tested".
Test by what?
By joy?
By food?
By blessing?
By breakthrough? What is that test?
Tell your neighour, "Without being tested, as a true believer, your genuineness cannot be determined.
You are not here today because of miracles you have seen so far.
You are not here today because of prophecies God is using me to perform.
No! You are not here because of crusades all over the world.
You are here because after sitting down,
"Ah, what this man has gone through - he is a man of God!"
No human being has gone through that and succeeded.
Did you listen to me?
You are not here because of the miracles.
You are not here because of prophecies or what you have seen on Emmanuel TV so far.
You are here because after sitting down and saying,
"Ha, he is not a human being! The man is a spirit!"
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Without being tested, as a Christian, your genuineness cannot be determined.
As a believer, we must understand that when times are stable
and the sea is calm and secure, no one is really tested.
When the oceans rise and thunders roar
I will soar with You above the storm
Father You are King over the flood
I will be still and know You are God
When the oceans rise and thunders roar
I will soar with You above the storm
Father You are King over the flood
I will be still and know You are God
Hide me now under Your wings
Cover me within Your mighty hand
When the oceans rise and thunders roar
I will soar with You above the storm
Father You are King over the flood
I will be still and know You are God
When the oceans rise and thunders roar
I will soar with You above the storm
Father You are King over the flood
I will be still and know You are God
You may be seated.
Yes.
We must understand that when times are stable
and the sea is calm and secure, no one is really tested.
Many abandon their faith because of challenges.
Many are running helter skelter.
The devil gets people to his side because of trouble.
When the trouble comes, the devil will say to you, "Can you see?
You say you are serving God. Can you see?
Where is your God?
God of crises? God of challenges?
God of tribulation? God of stagnation?
God of joblessness? Where is that God?"
In contrast, poverty, hardship, sickness, disease, stagnation, just name them
force us to come face to face with who we really are and what we can become.
Tell your neighbour, "Apply yourself to your duty, apply yourself to your work, as a Christian soldier".
I can't hear you.
[Apply yourself to your duty, apply yourself to your work, as a Christian soldier.]
Apply yourself to your duty, apply yourself to your work, as a Christian soldier.
What do I mean? Match your actions with your words if you want to succeed in life.
I'm no longer a slave to fear
I am a child of God
You unravel me with a melody
You surround me with a song
Of deliverance from my enemies'
'Til all my fears are gone
I'm no longer a slave to fear
I am a child of God
You may be seated. Thank you.
Hallelujah.
Apply yourself to your duty, apply yourself to your work, as a Christian soldier.
I mean, match your action with your word.
Your action is different from your word.
The action is heart; the word is mouth.
Your heart is different from your mouth; that is why your life is like this.
You find yourself in the situation you are in today because your heart is different from your mouth.
Match your action with your word.
Tell your neighbour.
[Match your action with your word.]
"In Jesus' name", "Jesus is this", "Jesus is that" - are you what you are saying?
"Amen!" - do you mean it?
"Amen! In Jesus' name, be healed!" - do you mean what you are saying?
Match your actions with your words.
Apply yourself to your duty, apply yourself to your work, as a Christian soldier.
Viewers, thank you for your time.
Now, you know your position when it comes to challenges.
You know your position when it comes to temptation.
You now know your position as a Christian when it comes to tribulation.
Now, you know your position when it comes to stagnation.
You know your position when it comes to temptation.
Here you are.
Temptation and challenges are your friends.
It is time now you begin to see the value in the challenges.
See the value in the situation that looks impossible.
There is value there.
I'm a good example.
Here I am.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Those of you who were crying for me in the past, now you can see.
Cry no more!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You never knew my situation didn't demand for crying.
Your sickness is to force you to look deeper.
Look deeper when sickness comes.
When hardship comes, look deeper.
Whatever you are facing, look deeper.
It is time to explore possibilities.
It will increase our desire and determination for God.
Pray and dream of other ways that might have been ignored.
I bless you. Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
TT: Mel Flowers 07/08/2018
RV ROBERT BEGIER 14/08/2018